# Stathis Moraitidis

# Senior Software Engineer

London, UK, London, UK

☑ emoraitidis@gmail.com ☐ +44 7514259526



I am a Senior/Lead Software Engineer with more than 10 years of experience and a backend and full stack focus. For the past few years I've worked mostly at startups so I am used to wearing many hats. I care deeply about building elegant and maintainable solutions, while keeping a great user and developer experience in mind.

#### SKILLS

#### **Backend** Frontend **Devops**

Python PostgreSQL MySQL Node C++ Java

HTML JavaScript / Typescript CSS React Redux

AWS (EC2, ECS, SNS, Lambda etc) GCP (GAE, GCE, Cloud Tasks, etc) Jenkins

### Other

Linux Git Unity OpenGL

#### WORK EXPERIENCE (4)

Senior Backend Engineer at Hopster

Jan 2020 - Dec 2020

Q London, (UK)

- Responsible for the automated monthly delivery of content to partners. This involved a combination of GAE, GCE, Cloud Tasks, etc.
- Owned all server-mobile APIs. I was the point of contact for existing implementations as well as all new development in the area.
- Implemented integrations around user login flows (e.g. Apple Sign In).
- Facilitated team processes, worked towards enhancing developer experience and tackling technical debt.

#### **Lead Software Engineer** at We Got Pop

Dec 2015 - Dec 2019

• London, (UK)

- Implemented various features across the company's stack and products. Technologies mostly used were Python, JavaScript, React, PostgreSQL and AWS.
- Overviewed larger-scale projects, keeping track of progress and feeding back to product team.
- Line-managed two colleagues.
- Helped more junior members of the team with their everyday queries.
- Conducted interviews for development and product teams.
- Helped in shaping and organising some of the team's processes.

## Software Engineer at IT2 Treasury Solutions

Sep 2013 - Nov 2015

## Q London, (UK)

- Implemented new functionality, enhancements and fixes, using C++, C, Microsoft SQL Server.
- Participated actively in meetings with product owners and managers during the planning process.

- Created a tool that unifies all developers' internal programs, making them easily accessible.
- Occasionally undertook team-leading responsibilities.

## Software Engineer at Fidessa

Jan 2011 - Sep 2013

**♀** Woking, (UK)

- Implemented a regression test framework for testing various products across the company. I was keeping track of new requests, resolving issues or assigning them to other team members.
- Ported a process (~8k lines) from Java to C++.
- Extended an existing web-based tool for testing market trading.

#### PROJECTS (1) -

## **Bit Pong**

https://github.com/strahius/bit-pong

A mobile and web game, built in JavaScript.

## **EDUCATION (2)**

MSc Computer Science at University of Piraeus

2007 - 2010

• Athens, (GR)
Grade: 9.4

BSc Economics at University of Athens

2001 - 2006

**Q** Athens, (GR) **Grade:** 6.5

#### **INTERESTS**

Movies				Games			Music	
	cinema	series	festivals	video games	board games		gigs	festivals
				development				

## **Sports**

basketball cycling table tennis